Finding Aid for the Verne Austin Papers, 1943-1945 LSC.2010.04
UCLA Library Special Collections
- The Japanese Situation at Tule Lake, 1.0 linear ft.
  - Documentary exhibits (Box 43, Box 44)
    - Minutes of the informal meeting of the divisional responsible men and the Project Director and Colonel Austin., January 17, 1944; (Mimeographed, 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - A WRA report on internee work crews., January 18, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - A WRA staff memorandum to Best., January 18, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
      re A census of the center.
    - Letter of appreciation by Best to the Coordinating Committee., [January 19, 1944]; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of the informal meeting of the coordinating committee and the Project Director and members of the Advisory Council., January 19, 1944; (Mimeographed, 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Confidential reports of the Office of Battalion Intelligence Officer on the death of Hayashi Tamotsu, stockade internee, and two premature babies., January 19, 1944; (3 items) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of the meeting of the Coordinating Committee and Best and Austin., January 20, 1944; (Mimeographed, 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - A copy of Gate no. 3 Check List, Tule Lake Project, Police Department., January 20, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Letter of appreciation by Raymon B. Hayward, Chief Project Steward, to Austin., January 22, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
      re Services rendered to Mess Operations by the detail assigned by Lieutenant Hagan.
      Also, minutes of the special meeting of the divisional heads of the Tule Lake Center, January 22, 1944 (mimeographed, 3pp.).
    - A WRA notice to internees issued by Best., January 27, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
      re Issuance of passes to all civilian personnel entering the Evacuee Residential Area.
    - Minutes of the special joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee of the Tule Lake Center., January 28, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of the regular meeting of the divisional heads of the Tule Lake Center., January 29, 1944; (Mimeographed, 3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Copies of Senate Joint Resolutions no.5,9., January 29, 31, 1944; January 31, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 8)
      no. 5, relative to substitution of United States Army for War Relocation Authority in the administration of Tule Lake Japanese Center and other internment camps, January 29, 1944
      no. 9, relative to memorializing Congress to provide for the deportation of alien and inimical Japanese at the conclusion of the present war, January 31, 1944.
    - Record of Events., February 1944; (7pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Best., February 2, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Nomination of Temporary Police Commissioners.
    - A WRA report on the numbers of evacuees reporting to work outside of the colony on January 27 & February 2, 1944., (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Copies of memoranda, Coordinating Committee to Project Director., February 2, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Receipt of Red Cross gift and creation of new employment opportunities.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Advisory Council members., February 2, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Preparation for referendum votes prior to the replacement of the Coordinating Committee.
    - Minutes of the special joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee of the Tule Lake Center., February 4, 1944; (Mimeographed. 3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the garage force of the Tule Lake Center., February 4, 1944; (Mimeographed. 6pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Report of the informal meeting of the stockade internees and the Coordinating Committee of the Tule Lake Center., February 5, 1944; (Mimeographed. 5pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - A report of T. Nagasawa, Manager of Block #6, to Civic Organization., February 7, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Sunday beating incident in the block office.
    - A copy of a statement, signed by 18 stockade internees pledging their support of the Coordinating Committee., February 8, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Forwarded to Austin.
    - Minutes of the joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., February 8, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - A copy of a letter forwarded to Best by some residents in Block #6., February 9, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Factional strife among the residents over the status quo question.
    - Memorandum forwarded by a group of internees opposing the Coordinating Committee to WRA Internal Security Chief., February 8, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Conditions with the view to nullifying the so-called policy of status quo.
    - Memoranda exchanged between the Army and the War Relocation Authority on the question of instituting a new system of escort for the Japanese garbage detail., February 9, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of the regular meeting of the divisional heads of the Tule Lake Center., February 12, 1944; (Mimeographed. 3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - A WRA report on the numbers of evacuees reporting to work outside of the colony., February 8 & 14, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Letter, S. Tateishi to Best., February 14, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Kai's plan.
    - Memoranda, Army officers to Austin., February 9 & 16, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Increased cost of food ration per day to Japanese internees.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Best and Advisory Council., February 16, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re the dissolution of the Coordinating Committee and the Formation of an Arrangement Committee prior to a general election.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Best and Advisory Council., February 16, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Recommendation of Takahashi Aizo, former Palo Alto resident and Issei community leader, as a possible leader in the colony.
    - Minutes of the regular meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., February 18, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Advisory Council., February 18, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Peace movement headed by Uji Iwao of Block 53, Ward 6.
    - WRA regulations governing hospital Sunday visit, effective Sunday., February 20, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - A notice to the internees by Austin., February 21, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Cancellation of the curfew order, Proclamation no. 2, November 13, 1944.
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp [characters], no. 1: The Tule Lake WRA Center Information Bulletin., February 22, 1944; (8pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      The first issue of the Tule Lake Center newspaper republished after three months' suspension since November 1944.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Austin., February 24, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Dissemination of proper information on the revocation of Army Proclamation no. 2.
    - Minutes of the regular meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., February 25, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Copies of letters of commendation, General D. McCoach, Jr., Commander of Ninth Service Command, to Austin., February 25, 1944; (4 pieces) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of the meeting of divisional responsible men and the Coordinating Committee., February 26, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Austin., February 28, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
      re Request for an interview with stockade internees.
    - Report of the special interview of the Coordinating Committee with the Stockade internees of the Tule Lake Center., February 28, 1944; (Mimeographed. 4pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Copies of the daily records of the Coordinating Committee., February 1-29, 1944; (8pp.) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Record of Events., March 1944; (7pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of the regular joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., March 3, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum, Byron Akitsuki, Executive Secretary of the Coordinating Committee, to the Advisory Council., March 3, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Resignation.
    - A copy of a report by J.B. O'Brien, WRA Police Officer., March 3, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Trial of 23 Japanese internees at Tule Lake Center on various charges to be heard before the courts in Alturas, Modoc County, California, on March 6, 1944.
    - Travel authorization issued by H.L. Black, Acting Project Director of Tule Lake Center., March 6, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      For 23 Japanese internees being taken to Alturas to appear before the courts.
    - A confidential report by Lieutenant A. Forbes, Jr., Military Police Officer., March 6, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re An increasing feeling of dissatisfaction among the internees with the attitude of WRA toward the Coordinating Committee and the Colony.
    - Memorandum, H.L. Black, Acting Project Director, to Austin., March 6, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Procedure for screening justifiable detainees out of the stockade.
    - The Writ of Habeas Corpus Ad Testificandum, issued by Judge M.I. Welsh, United States District Court., March 6, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      For the appearance of 5 Japanese internees in the Tule Lake Center to testify before the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California, Sacramento, on March 14, 1944.
    - Minutes of the joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., March 7, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - A typewritten memo of the Coordinating Committee., March 7, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re a growing tense atmosphere in the Colony since the recent arrival of Manzanites.
    - A translated copy of an anonymous leaflet titled True picture of this center., March 7, 1944; (3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - The Writ of Habeas Corpus Ad Testificandum, issued by United States District Court for the Northern District of California., March 8, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      For the appearance of a Japanese internee at Tule Lake to testify before the court.
    - Sketch of Tule Lake Center and Martial Law, by Yasu Kaito., February 25, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      An English translation of an article published in the Rocky Shimpo, a Japanese language newspaper in Denver, Colorado.
    - Minutes of the joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the Coordinating Committee., March 10, 1944; (Mimeographed. 3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of the regular meeting of the divisional responsible men and the Coordinating Committee., March 11, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Austin., March 2, 1944; (2 items) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Request for permit to grant assignments to farm supervisors; and memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Best, February 11, 1944. re Recommendation for agricultural department's chief, supervisor, and assistant supervisor.
    - A copy of a letter, Captain B.N. Hartman, Security Officer, to WRA Personnel Officer., March 21, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re the opening of Army files to WRA personnel for information on Japanese applying for work.
    - Letter, Hayden Saunders, U.S. Marshal in Sacramento, to Austin., March 28, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Warrants for three Japanese internees at Tule Lake.
    - A certified copy of a letter, H.L. Black, to Akashi Sanae., March 29, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Permission to circulate a petition on the question of segregating those internees who desire repatriation from the rest.
    - A copy of a petition circulated in the Colony to obtain signatures of those internees who desired earliest possible repatriation to Japan., ca. March 29, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - A copy of a sworn statement made by Austin., March 30, 1944; (6pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
      re Confiscation of contraband articles in the possessions of Japanese internees at Tule Lake as a result of the November 26, 1943 search operation.
    - Copies of the daily records of the Coordinating Committee., March 1-31, 1944; (10pp.) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Record of Events., April 1944; (6pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to WRA., April 6, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Priority on the first exchange ship.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Black., April 7, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Recommendation to give explanation to confused Colonists regarding a census being taken by a committee on repatriates and expatriates.
    - Memorandum, Coordinating Committee to Lieutenant Forbes., April 7, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Resignation of all Coordinating Committee members.
    - Minutes of the meeting of the divisional responsible men and the Coordinating Committee., April 8, 1944; (Mimeographed. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - The Newell Star, vol. 1, no. 6., April 13, 1944; (6pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp [characters], no. 8., April 13, 1944; (4pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Minutes of the joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the delegates of the divisional responsible men., April 14, 1944; (Typewritten. 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the divisional responsible men., April 15, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "5 Agitators Jailed at Tule Lake". A clipping from the San Francisco Examiner., April 18, 1944; (1 piece) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the divisional responsible men., April 18, 1944; (Typewritten. 2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Memorandum, Headquarters, Ninth Service Command, to Commanding Officers of Security Districts., April 18, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Hirohito's Birthday on April 29, 1944.
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the police representatives and the police commissioners of the Tule Lake Center., April 19, 1944; (Mimeographed. 5pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Letter, John C. Baker, Chief of Reports Division, WRA, to Best., April 19, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Request for duplicate copies of documentary materials re the administration of the Tule Lake Center by the Army.
    - The Newell Star, vol. 1, no. 7., April 20, 1944; (6pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp, no. 9., April 20, 1944; (4pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Minutes of the joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the delegates of the divisional responsible men., April 21, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - The Newell Star, vol. 1, no. 8., April 22, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp, no. 9, Special Issue., April 22, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Letter, Mrs. Violet Matsuda to Austin., April 24, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Sending home-prepared food to those confined in the stockade on the boy's day.
    - Memorandum, Best to Austin., April 27, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      re Retrieving golf balls between warning fence and manproof fence.
    - Minutes of the final joint meeting of the Advisory Council and the delegates of the divisional responsible men., April 28, 1944; (Typewritten. 3pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - An itemized list of extra food sent to the stockade to celebrate the Emperor's Birthday at the special request of WRA Project Director., April 29, 1944; (1p.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Minutes of the final meeting of the divisional responsible men., April 29, 1944; (Mimeographed. 4pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Translated copies of the minutes of the meetings of the Daihyshakai (held October 17, 23, & 28; November 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 12, 14, 16, 17, & 18; and December 1, 4, 5 & 19, 1943)., April 30, 1944; (85pp.) (Box 43, Folder 11)
      Translated from the notes of the secretary. Received from the Coordinating Committee.
    - Record of Events., May 1944; (6pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum, Best to all residents of the Center., May 1, 1944; (6pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Formation of a representative committee.
    - Memorandum, Best to Lieutenant Schaner, Prison Officer., May 2, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Request for statistical information on the internees in the Army stockade.
    - A copy of the report of the Coordinating Committee to the Spanish Consul (Received on May 2, 1944)., n.d.; (Typewritten. 11pp. + 1 enclosure. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Copies of a talk made by Royal A. Gunnison over the Mutual Network after his visit to Tule Lake., May 3, 1944; (3pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum, Battalion Intelligence Officer to Austin., May 11, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Investigation by an FBI agent.
    - A report submitted by Sergeant. Yeramian, investigator., May 11, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Rumors in the Colony that the Army and WRA cannot get along.
    - Confidential reports from the Office of Battalion Intelligence Officer., May 15 & 16, 1944; (5 reports) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Activities and attitudes of Rosalie Hankie, a research worker on the Japanese problem, and Elizabeth Wewell, a missionary, who visited the Tule Lake Center.
    - A report by Sergeant Yeramian., May 16, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Ando Chuichi, mental case.
    - Memorandum, R.S. Armstrong, Provost Marshal, to Austin., May 17, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Escorts furnished by a false request.
    - A report on block meetings and recommendations., May 19, 1944; (5pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Includes tabulated records on attendance.
    - Memorandum, Best to Austin., May 22, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Complete internal administration of the stockade by WRA.
    - Memorandum, Best to Austin., May 22, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re A simplified procedure for the release of the internees in the stockade.
    - Special Orders no. 126, Hq., Camp Tule Lake., May 24, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re A board of four officers to investigate the shooting of Okamoto Shoichi by Private Bernard W. Goe at the old main gate where Pvt. Goe was posted as a sentry.
    - A report submitted by T.F. Edwards, Medical Officer, on the death of Okamoto., May 25, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Extra. The Newell Star, Supplement., May 25, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re the shooting incident and the death of Okamoto Shoichi.
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp tokuho [Extra], no. 14., May 25, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - The Newell Star, vol. 1, no. 13., May 25, 1944; (6pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Tsuru Reiko Shimp, no. 14., May 25, 1944; (4pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - A copy of the Inquisition made by the Coroner's Jury on the body of Okamoto Shoichi., May 26, 1944; (1 item) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the divisional responsible men., May 26, 1944; (Mimeographed. 3pp.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum, divisional responsible men to Best., May 27, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
      re Recommendations on the Okamoto incident.
    - Minutes of the informal meeting of the representatives of the divisional responsible men and the Project Director., May 30, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - A typewritten copy of the speech made by R.R. Best at the funeral of Okamoto Shoichi., May 31, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Record of Events., June 1944; (6pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - A report by Sergeant Yeramian., June 2, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Information obtained from Rosalie Hankey, a researcher.
    - Reports submitted by Private Samuel Shank on an alleged attack made by a Japanese on him., June 6, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Memoranda issued by the Army and WRA to clarify the pass procedure at Gate no. 3., June 6, 7 & 8, 1944; (3 pieces) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Memorandum no. 87., June 8, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      An order issued by Austin to restrict the entry of Army personnel to the segregee residential area without a pass signed by the Commanding Officer.
    - Memorandum, W.E. Schmidt, Chief of Administrative Police Department, WRA, to Austin., June 7, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Issuance of badges to two new members of the department.
    - A report on rumors in the Colony., June 12, 1944; (Typewritten. 1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Memorandum, Y. Nitomi, General Manager of the Tule Lake Cooperative Enterprises, Inc., to Best., June 9, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Establishment of a photographic studio in the Colony. Forwarded for Austin's approval.
    - Office memorandum, WRA Administrative Police Department to Austin., June 15, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Resignation of two members of the department.
    - A copy of the Confidential Report of WRA Community Analysis Section on Community reactions to the Okamoto Incident -- Tule LakeMay 27, 1944., June 21, 1944; (12pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Written by Dr. Opler, WRA analyst. Received by Austin.
    - WRA Community Analysis Report on the Okamoto Funeral Ceremony and pending decision in the case, June 4, 1944., June 21, 1944; (5pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Written by Dr. Opler and received by Austin.
    - Minutes of the special meeting of the divisional responsible men., May 26, 1944; (Mimeographed. 3pp.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Minutes of the informal meeting of the representatives of the divisional responsible men and the Project Director., May 30, 1944; (Mimeographed. 1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - A report by Battalion Intelligence Officer., June 22, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Shigeo Okamoto assault case.
    - A report by Battalion Intelligence Officer., June 23, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      re Rumors from the Colony: Frank Furukawa, former head of the Civic Organization.
    - Record of Events., July 1944; (5pp.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - A report by Sergeant Yeramian., July 1, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re Information obtained from Rosalie Hankey, a researcher, on the Colony.
    - A report by Battalion Intelligence Officer., July 3, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re Murder of Hitomi Yaozo and an attack on Takahashi Aizo.
    - Japanese citizenship. A typewritten extract from the San Francisco Examiner article., July 4, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - A copy of a petition forwarded by former members of the Coordinating Committee to the Secretary of Interior, Harold L. Ickes., July 8, 1944; (4pp.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re assistance to bring an end to the reign of terrorists in the Tule Lake Center.
    - A report by Battalion Intelligence Officer., July 11, 1944; (2pp.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) and its investigation of the confinement of internees in the Army stockade.
    - A copy of a protest petition signed by those Japanese segregated in the hospital under protective custody, who refused to return to the Colony as ordered by Best., July 13, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - A mimeographed announcement of the Japanese Colonial Police Department to the residents in the colony., July 14, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re Opinion poll on the dissolution of the police department.
    - A copy of an anonymous letter sent to WRA Internal Security Officer., July 17, 1944; (1p.) (Box 44, Folder 3)
      re Agitators in Block 49, Ward 6.